# Gorav Sharma

Pilani, Rajasthan 9649196949 gscs031@gmail.com



# Summary

Deadline-Oriented Software Tester with 3+ year experience in Manual testing Environment. Easily collaborate with the developers and Project Managers to accomplish Milestones. Solid history of discovering errors, resolving defects, and ensuring client expectations are met with high- quality software solutions.

## **Academic Qualifications**

Examination	Year	Board	College	Marks
B.tech	2017	Rajasthan	B K Birla Institute of Engineering and	57.98%
		Technical	Technology, Pilani	
		University		
12th	2013	RBSE	Tagore Children Academy, Surajgarh	62.80%
10th	2011	RBSE	D.P.S School, Surajgarh	69.00%

# **Employment History**

#### 1. Marketing Mindz

Software Tester Jaipur, Rajasthan October 2018 – December 2019

Worked as a software Tester in Marketing Mindz.

#### 2. NineHertz India

Quality Analyst Jaipur, Rajasthan December 2019 – Present

Working as a Quality Analyst in NineHertz India Private Limited.

### **Professional Skills**

- Programming Languages- C,C++,Core Java basics
- Database-Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL
- Operating Systems-DOS, Windows XP/Vista/7, Linux
- Software-Photoshop, Matlab, MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint
- Understanding of SDLC and STLC
- Agile Approach
- Requirement Analysis
- Use Cases
- Test Plan
- **Test Cases**
- Bug Life Cycle
- **Smoke Testing**
- Sanity Testing
- **Integration Testing**
- **Regression Testing** System Testing
- **Interface Testing**
- Beta/Acceptance Testing
- Back-end testing
- Browser compatibility Testing
- **Boundary Value Testing**
- Black box testing
- Alpha Testing
- Negative Testing
- **Functional Testing Equivalence Portioning**
- Performance Testing

- Happy path Testing
- Monkey Testing
- Test Report
- Have the knowledge of ERP projects testing.
- Have the knowledge of Vtiger projects testing.
- Have the knowledge of plugin testing.
- Have the knowledge of testing from wordpress-Backend.
- Have the basic knowledge of API testing.

# **Training**

• SUMMER training on "CORE JAVA" at HPE JAIPUR for duration of 2 months.

# **Projects**

#### **Chilling:**

Chilling is a mobile application which built on react platform. In the chilling app user can listen the stories like horror stories, scary stories, true stories, thriller stories, ghost stories and many more. I have done the complete testing for both mobile application (Android and IOS) including admin panel. This app is now live on Play store and App store. And having the 80,000+ users.

#### Dokpam:

Dokpam is a mobile application which built on react platform. It has two different-different applications for the doctors and patients. In this application users can schedule the video, chat and In-clinic appointments for self and family member. And can also manage the medical history of all the members and can share this medical history with the doctors. I have done the complete testing of these both apps including backend. These both apps are live now on App store and Play store. And having the total 500+verified doctors and 10000+ Users.

#### Dogpack:

Dogpack is a mobile application which built on react platform. This app is related to the dogs. Any user can register his account on the app and can add their dogs. It is having the map where it shows the nearby park(dynamic from backend). And dog can check-in the park, can schedule there check-in, follow the parks, create the post, add the pack members and chat with them, like and comment on the post, suggest any park and many more. And dogs also getting the badges on his activities. And and also getting the treats. It also having the store option. From here you can purchase the items by the earned treats. I have done the complete testing of this app including backend. This app is live now on App store and Play Store and having the 15000+ users.

#### **Money Hunter:**

Money hunter is website and also have the mobile applications which built on react platform. In this website admin will create the hunts from the admin panel which will show on the frontend. And each hunt will have the time limit like 2 days, 3 days. After this time user can give the answer of asked question. And after the collect the answers, admin will declare the winner from the admin panel. So this is the basic flow of the project. And I have done the whole testing of this project. It's web panel is live now and mobile application will be live in January.

#### **Ship Junction**

This project was based on the shiprocket. Here we can add our ecommerce stores like Open cart, magento, shopify and other. And also integrate the different-different couriers. And from here user can ship the all order of these stores by different-different courier services like xpressbees, fedex, DHL, Blue Dart, DTDC and Gati. This project is live now.

#### Techvedi

It is a ecommerce mobile app for android. Having three types of login in app and two logins of admin.

Mobile App: User, Vendor, Driver Admin: Super Admin, Manufacturer

From here any user can buy products, vendor can add his products and purchase the product from manufacturer. And driver will able to deliver the products to user. And super admin has all the access of order products and other things. And manufacturer can put his products here for sell. I have tested whole design and functionality for this application.

This app is live now on play store.

#### MyCrowdx:

It is a PWA based project. Having two types of login, Creator and Follower. Here creator can add his Subscription plan, Chat subscription plan, Free post, Paid post, Bundle subscriptions. And any follower and creator have the need to purchase these plans for chat and view post. I have tested these whole site design, functionality and admin panel also. This website is live now.

#### JNPT(Jawahar Lal Nehru Port Trust) (Government Project)

This was a Mobile application for Android and IOS. I make the complete test cases for this project and I tested the both apps and the admin panel also. Now these both apps are available on the App store and Play Store.

#### **ICAR-DCR(Government Project)**

This was a website for the farmers to calculate fertilizer, Lime, convertors and others. By this farmer can calculate the above mention things for his soil. And I make the test case for this website and tested the complete website with responsive and also make the test report. And also test the website on different operating systems and also test the responsive on different browsers like Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, Safari, Internet Explorer and also test in android,i-pad,IOS.

#### Midhani(Mishra Dhatu Nigam Limited)(Government Project)

This was an official website of this company. I make the test cases for this website and tested the complete website according to the government guidelines(GIGW). And also make the test report for the website and also for the government guidelines. And also test the website on different operating systems and also test the responsive on different browsers like Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, Safari, Internet Explorer and also test in android,i-pad,IOS.

#### ICAR-Cashew(Government Project)

This was an android mobile application for the cashews. I have tested both back-end and application. This application is live now on play store with the name cashew india.

#### Other Projects:-

ERP, Vtiger-CRM, Biocoiff, Biocoiff-pro, Biocoiff-CRM, Achoo-Allergy, Dual-Login, Downsdump, TMM-Industry, TMM-Training, Racorstore, Amazing-kids, Millborn, Wug-Wug, IUS-Audit, Sparq, TMM-Info, 9-yards, Raj-Yatayat, Music Bubble, OMY, Music Stream, Tea Talk, V-wellness and others.

### **Seminar Presentation**

• Seminar presentations on "CORE JAVA" and "MIND READING COMPUTER".

#### **Achievements**

#### Academic

- Top 5% in CoCubes coding test.
- Coordinated various college events in quasar(Inter-college sports fest).
- Managing director of BASANT(Inter-college cultural fest).
- Organized Blood Donation Camp In college.

#### **Sports**

• Regional level kabbaddi player(Inter schools junior kabbaddi championship).

#### Cultural

- Participated in "Ramp walk" in Basant(Inter College cultural festival).
- Runner up of various fashion competitions.

#### **Awards**

• Employee Of The Quarter for the outstanding performance(Mar 2019-Jun 2019)

## **Hobbies& Interests**

- Swimming
- Cricket
- gardenirMovies gardening

# Languages

- Hindi
- English

## **Personal Details**

Date of Birth 10-06-1998 Nationality Indian Marital Status Single

Permanent Address Vill-Cheema ka bass, Post-Berla, Tehsil-Surajgarh

District-Jhunjhunu, Rajasthan, 333033

9649196949 Contact

## **Declaration**

I hereby declare that all the information contained in this resume is in accordance with facts or truths to my knowledge. I take full responsibility for the correctness of the said information.

Place: Jaipur **Signature**